How would one go about analyzing the dependency labels and the relationships between the tokens, to identify the main clauses and phrases to make a simpler sentences.

Given "An operator must obtain verifiable parental consent before any collection, use, or disclosure of personal information from children, including consent to any material change in the collection, use, or disclosure practices to which the parent has previously consented."

the main verb is "must obtain", the subject is "An operator", and the object is "verifiable parental consent". 

The modifying clauses are 
"before any collection, use, or disclosure of personal information from children" and 
"including consent to any material change in the collection, use, or disclosure practices to which the parent has previously consented". 

Using this information, you can construct the following simpler sentences:

"An operator must obtain verifiable parental consent."
"Any collection, use, or disclosure of personal information from children requires verifiable parental consent."
"Verifiable parental consent is required for any material change in the collection, use, or disclosure practices to which the parent has previously consented."



#2
An operator must give the parent the option to consent to the collection and use of the child's personal information without consenting to disclosure of his or her personal information to third parties.

"An operator must give the parent the option to consent to the collection and use of the child's personal information."
"An operator must give the parent the option to consent to the collection and use of the child's personal information without consenting to disclosure of his or her personal information to third parties."
"An operator must give the parent the option to consent to the collection and use of the child's personal information, and the parent must not consent to disclosure of his or her personal information to third parties."


#3