<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="cfr.xsl"?>
<CFRGRANULE xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="CFRMergedXML.xsd">
  <FDSYS>
    <CFRTITLE>21</CFRTITLE>
    <CFRTITLETEXT>Food and Drugs</CFRTITLETEXT>
    <VOL>1</VOL>
    <DATE>2018-04-01</DATE>
    <ORIGINALDATE>2018-04-01</ORIGINALDATE>
    <COVERONLY>false</COVERONLY>
    <TITLE>Electronic signature components and controls.</TITLE>
    <GRANULENUM>Â§ 11.200</GRANULENUM>
    <HEADING>Section Â§ 11.200</HEADING>
    <ANCESTORS>
      <PARENT HEADING="Title 21" SEQ="4">Food and Drugs</PARENT>
      <PARENT HEADING="CHAPTER I" SEQ="3">FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION, DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</PARENT>
      <PARENT HEADING="SUBCHAPTER A" SEQ="2">GENERAL</PARENT>
      <PARENT HEADING="PART 11" SEQ="1">ELECTRONIC RECORDS; ELECTRONIC SIGNATURES</PARENT>
      <PARENT HEADING="Subpart C" SEQ="0">Electronic Signatures</PARENT>
    </ANCESTORS>
  </FDSYS>
  <SECTION>
    <SECTNO>§11.200</SECTNO>
    <SUBJECT>Electronic signature components and controls.</SUBJECT>
    <P>(a) Electronic signatures that are not based upon biometrics shall:</P>
    <P>(1) Employ at least two distinct identification components such as an identification code and password.</P>
    <P>(i) When an individual executes a series of signings during a single, continuous period of controlled system access, the first signing shall be executed using all electronic signature components; subsequent signings shall be executed using at least one electronic signature component that is only executable by, and designed to be used only by, the individual.</P>
    <P>(ii) When an individual executes one or more signings not performed during a single, continuous period of controlled system access, each signing shall be executed using all of the electronic signature components.</P>
    <P>(2) Be used only by their genuine owners; and<PRTPAGE P="201"/>
    </P>
    <P>(3) Be administered and executed to ensure that attempted use of an individual's electronic signature by anyone other than its genuine owner requires collaboration of two or more individuals.</P>
    <P>(b) Electronic signatures based upon biometrics shall be designed to ensure that they cannot be used by anyone other than their genuine owners.</P>
  </SECTION>
</CFRGRANULE>
